why my parents made me follow the rules that they did.
لماذا أجبرني أبواي على اتباع القوانين التي وضعاها.
Like, why did I really have to mow the lawn?
مثل، لماذا عليّ حقًا أن أقص الحشيش؟
Why was homework really that important?
لماذا كان الواجب المدرسي حقًا بتلك الأهمية؟
Why couldn't I put jelly beans in my oatmeal?
لماذا لا أستطيع وضع الحلوى في صحن الشوفان خاصتي؟
My childhood was abound with questions like this.
كانت طفولي تزخر بأسئلة كهذه.
Normal things about being a kid and realizing that sometimes,
عن الأشياء العادية بشأن كوني طفلًا وإدراك بأنه في بعض الأحيان،
it was best to listen to my parents even when I didn't exactly understand why.
كان الأفضل هو الاستماع إلى والديّ حتى عندما لم أكن أفهم السبب بالضبط.
And it's not that they didn't want me to think critically.
الأمر ليس أنهم لم يريدوا مني التفكير بعمق.
Their parenting always sought to reconcile the tension
إن تربيتهم لنا سعت دومًا إلى تسوية التوتر
between having my siblings and I understand the realities of the world,
بين جعلي أنا وأخوتي نفهم حقائق العالم،
while ensuring that we never accepted the status quo as inevitable.
بينما يتأكدون من أننا لن نقبل بالوضع الراهن كأمر حتمي.
I came to realize that this, in and of itself,
وأدركت بأن هذا، في حد ذاته،
was a very purposeful form of education.
كان يمثل شكلًا هادفًا من التعليم.
One of my favorite educators, Brazilian author and scholar Paulo Freire,
إن أحد معلميَّ المفضلين، الكاتب والباحث باولو فريير،
speaks quite explicitly about the need for education
يتحدث بوضوح كبير عن الحاجة إلى استخدام التعليم
to be used as a tool for critical awakening and shared humanity.
كأداة للصحوة البناءة والإنسانية المشتركة.
In his most famous book, "Pedagogy of the Oppressed,"
وفي أشهر كتاب له، "علم أصول تدريس المضطهدين"،
he states, "No one can be authentically human
يقول: "لا أحد يمكنه أن يكون إنسانًا أصيلًا
while he prevents others from being so."
بينما يمنع الآخرين من أن يكونوا كذلك".
I've been thinking a lot about this lately, this idea of humanity,
مؤخرًا، قد فكرت كثيرًا بهذا الأمر، فكرة الإنسانية،
and specifically, who in this world is afforded the privilege
وبالتحديد، من يُمنحون الامتياز في هذا العالم
of being perceived as fully human.
بأن ينظر إلى الواحد منهم على أنه إنسان كامل.
Over the course of the past several months,
وعلى مدار الأشهر العديدة الماضية،
the world has watched as unarmed black men, and women,
شاهد العالم مقتل رجال ونساء سود
have had their lives taken at the hands of police and vigilante.
على يد الشرطة والملثمين.
These events and all that has transpired after them
هذه الأحداث وما تبعها
have brought me back to my own childhood
قد عادت بي إلى مرحلة الطفولة
and the decisions that my parents made about raising a black boy in America
والقرارات التي اتخذها أبواي بشأن تنشئة طفل أسود في أمريكا،
that growing up, I didn't always understand in the way that I do now.
وهو ما لم أفهمه خلال مراحل نشأتي كما أفهمه الآن.
I think of how hard it must have been, how profoundly unfair it must have felt
أفكر في مدى صعوبة الأمور أيامها، ومدى عمق الظلم الذي كانوا يشعرون به
for them to feel like they had to strip away parts of my childhood
وكأنهم كانوا مجبرين على انتزاع أجزاء من طفولتي
just so that I could come home at night.
فقط كي أعود سالمًا إلى البيت في الليل.
For example, I think of how one night,
على سبيل المثال، أفكر في ليلة واحدة،
when I was around 12 years old, on an overnight field trip to another city,
عندما كان عمري حوالي 12 سنة، في رحلة ليلية إلى مدينة أخرى،
my friends and I bought Super Soakers
قمت أنا وأصدقائي بشراء مسدسات ماء
and turned the hotel parking lot into our own water-filled battle zone.
وحولنا ساحة انتظار السيارات بالفندق إلى أرض معركة مملوءة بالمياه.
We hid behind cars,
اختبئنا خلف السيارات،
running through the darkness that lay between the streetlights,
نركض في الظلام الكائن بين مصابيح الشوارع،
boundless laughter ubiquitous across the pavement.
مع ضحكات لا تنتهي تملؤ المكان.
But within 10 minutes,
ولكن خلال 10 دقائق،
my father came outside, grabbed me by my forearm
خرج أبي وأمسك بي من ساعدي
and led me into our room with an unfamiliar grip.
وقادني إلى داخل غرفتي بقبضة غير معهودة.
Before I could say anything,
وقبل أن أستطيع قول أي شيء،
tell him how foolish he had made me look in front of my friends,
قبل أن أخبره كم جعل منظري غبيًا أمام أصدقائي،
he derided me for being so naive.
سخِرَ منّي لكوني ساذجًا.
Looked me in the eye, fear consuming his face,
نظر والدي إليّ في عيني، والخوف يملأ وجهه،
and said, "Son, I'm sorry,
وقال "آسف يا بنيَّ،
but you can't act the same as your white friends.
ولكنك لا تستطيع التصرف مثل أصدقائك البيض.
You can't pretend to shoot guns.
لا تستطيع التظاهر بإطلاق الرصاص.
You can't run around in the dark.
لا تستطيع الجري في الظلام.
You can't hide behind anything other than your own teeth."
لا تستطيع الاختباء خلف أي شيء غير لسانك".
I know now how scared he must have been,
أعلم الآن مدى الخوف الذي كان يعيش فيه،
how easily I could have fallen into the empty of the night,
مدى سهولة وقوعي في فراغ الليل،
that some man would mistake this water
بأن أحدًا ربما يخطئ الماء
for a good reason to wash all of this away.
لسبب جيد حتى يمسح كل هذا.
These are the sorts of messages I've been inundated with my entire life:
هذه أنواع من الرسائل التي كانت تلاحقني طيلة حياتي:
Always keep your hands where they can see them, don't move too quickly,
دائمًا أبقِ يديك في مكان يرونها فيه، لا تتحرك بسرعة،
take off your hood when the sun goes down.
انزع قبعتك عندما تغرب الشمس.
My parents raised me and my siblings in an armor of advice,
أنشأنا أبواي، أنا وأخوتي، في درع النصيحة،
an ocean of alarm bells so someone wouldn't steal the breath from our lungs,
محيط من أجراس الإنذار حتى لا يستطيع أحد سرقة النفس من رئاتنا،
so that they wouldn't make a memory of this skin.
وحتى لا يستطيع أحد جعل هذا الجلد ذكرى.
So that we could be kids, not casket or concrete.
حتى نكون أطفالًا، لا توابيت ولا إسمنت.
And it's not because they thought it would make us better than anyone else
وذلك ليس لأنهم اعتقدوا بأن ذلك يجعلنا أفضل من أي شخص آخر،
it's simply because they wanted to keep us alive.
إنه ببساطة لأنهم أرادوا إبقائنا على قيد الحياة.
All of my black friends were raised with the same message,
نشأ كل أصدقائي السود مع نفس الرسالة،
the talk, given to us when we became old enough
المحادثات، التي أعطيت لنا عندما كبرنا بما فيه الكفاية
to be mistaken for a nail ready to be hammered to the ground,
ليلقى باللوم علينا بسبب مسمار جاهز ليُدقّ في الأرض.
when people made our melanin synonymous with something to be feared.
عندما جعل الناس الميلانين خاصتنا مرادفًا لشيء يخافون منه.
But what does it do to a child
ولكن ماذا يفعل ذلك لطفلٍ
to grow up knowing that you cannot simply be a child?
إن نمى وهو يعلم بأنه ببساطة لا يستطيع أن يكون طفلًا؟
That the whims of adolescence are too dangerous for your breath,
أن نزوات المراهقة خطيرة جدًا على حياتك،
that you cannot simply be curious,
أنك ببساطة لا تستطيع أن تكون فضوليًا،
that you are not afforded the luxury of making a mistake,
أنك لا تُمنح ترف ارتكاب الأخطاء،
that someone's implicit bias
أن التحيز التام عند شخص ما
might be the reason you don't wake up in the morning.
ربما يكون السبب في أن لا تستيقظ صباحًا.
But this cannot be what defines us.
ولكن هذا لا يمكن أن يقوم بتعريفنا.
Because we have parents who raised us to understand
لأن لدينا آباء أنشأونا لكي نفهم
that our bodies weren't meant for the backside of a bullet,
بأن أجسامنا لم تُعدّ للجانب الآخر من الرصاصة،
but for flying kites and jumping rope, and laughing until our stomachs burst.
ولكن لتطيير الطائرات الورقية والقفز على الحبل والضحك حتى ننفجر من السعادة.
We had teachers who taught us how to raise our hands in class,
لقد كان لدينا أساتذة علمونا كيف نرفع أيدينا في الصف،
and not just to signal surrender,
ليس فقط للإشارة بالضعف،
and that the only thing we should give up
وأن الشيء الوحيد الذي يجب أن نتخلى عنه
is the idea that we aren't worthy of this world.
هو فكرة أننا لسنا جديرين بالعيش في هذا العالم.
So when we say that black lives matter, it's not because others don't,
إذًا عندما نقول بأن أرواح السود مهمة، ذلك ليس لأن حياة غيرهم غير مهمة،
it's simply because we must affirm that we are worthy of existing without fear,
إنها ببساطة لأننا يجب أن نؤكد بأننا نستحق العيش دون خوف،
when so many things tell us we are not.
عندما تخبرنا الكثير من الأشياء بأننا لا نستحق.
I want to live in a world where my son
أريد أن أحيا في عالم حيث
will not be presumed guilty the moment he is born,
لا يُفترض بأن ابني مذنب منذ لحظة ولادته،
where a toy in his hand isn't mistaken for anything other than a toy.
حيث لا يخطئون اللعبة في يده على أنها شي آخر غير اللعبة.
And I refuse to accept that we can't build this world into something new,
وأرفض القبول بأننا لا نستطيع تعمير هذا العالم إلى شيء جديد،
some place where a child's name
مكان حيث اسم الطفل
doesn't have to be written on a t-shirt, or a tombstone,
لا ينبغي أن يكون مكتوبًا على قميصٍ أو شاهدةِ قبر،
where the value of someone's life
حيث قيمة حياة شخص ما
isn't determined by anything other than the fact that they had lungs,
لا يقررها شيء غير الحقيقة بأن لديهم أرواح،
a place where every single one of us can breathe.
مكان يستطيع فيه كل واحد منا أن يتنفس.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)